nasdaq.com 2019-06-19

# Privacy Statement - GDPR Policy | Nasdaq

Effective Date: May 25, 2018

As a global financial services and technology provider and self-regulatory organization, Nasdaq is committed to protecting Personal Information and complying with applicable privacy requirements in a trustworthy, transparent and responsible manner.

This Privacy Policy describes how Nasdaq, Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “Nasdaq,” “we,” “our” or “us”) collects, uses and discloses Personal Information about individuals (collectively, “users” or “you”) receiving our products and services, exploring or maintaining a business relationship with us (either directly or through an intermediary such as your financial services provider, your appointed legal or other representative or your employer) and/or using our websites or online features (each a “Site” or collectively, our “Sites”). As used in this Privacy Policy, Personal Information means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person; Personal Information is intended to cover all information subject to personal data processing and privacy laws applicable to our business.

Without limiting the generality of the preceding paragraph, this Privacy Policy applies to all Personal Information provided to Nasdaq’s European exchanges (namely, Nasdaq Copenhagen A/S, Nasdaq Helsinki Ltd, Nasdaq Iceland hf., Nasdaq Oslo A/S, Nasdaq Riga AS, Nasdaq Stockholm AB, Nasdaq Tallinn AS and AB Nasdaq Vilnius), the clearinghouse Nasdaq Clearing AB, central shares depositories (namely, Nasdaq CSD SE and Nasdaq CSD Iceland hf.), AB Pensionkeskus, and the broker-dealer/investment firm Nasdaq Broker Services AB (collectively, our “EEA Regulated Entities”) subject only to the [exclusions](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61803) from this policy set forth below.

The Privacy Policy also describes your rights, where applicable, and how to exercise them. You may contact us at any time with questions related to our Personal Information processing and privacy via email at [privacy@nasdaq.com](mailto:privacy@nasdaq.com).

In some instances, we may post or provide materials that provide further description of Personal Information processing related to certain products and services. We may also post information about how we comply with specific Personal Information laws or regulations like European Union or United States privacy laws. Such materials are for informational purposes only and are not intended as an exhaustive listing of Personal Information processing related to the product and service. The materials should not be construed as modifying this Privacy Policy.

## Brief overview

  |     
---|---  
**Information about how this policy applies to our global company** |  Nasdaq has endeavored to develop a Privacy Policy that can be applied consistently across its global organization; however, certain elements are limited to situations where applicable law requires them. With respect to your Personal Information, the data controller will be the Nasdaq entity delivering products and services or with whom you are interacting. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61802) to learn more.   
**Situations where this Privacy Policy does not apply** |  This Privacy Policy does not apply to the extent that other Personal Information processing or privacy terms are set forth in the applicable contract for Nasdaq’s products or services, posted on a Site or in certain other situations. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61803) to learn more   
**Information we collect about you** |  We may collect Personal Information and Device Information (defined below) (collectively, “information”) about you in connection with your (or your employer’s) receipt of products or services including to fulfill our contractual obligations or establish or maintain a business relationship with us; your registration, use, purchase, or inquiries on or about our Sites that link to this Privacy Policy; the pursuit of our legitimate business interests; and/or, to comply with applicable law. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61776) to learn more.   
**How we use your information** |  We may use your information to provide services; respond to inquiries and provide customer support and technical assistance; communicate with you; process transactions; improve, develop, provide content for, operate, deliver and market our products, service or Sites; implement social networking features; comply with our company policies and procedures and with applicable law; ensure proper and authorized use of the Sites; perform Site tracking and analysis; and, as otherwise permitted by applicable law. Click here to learn more. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61816) to learn more.   
**Automated decision-making** |  We do not process Personal Information for automated decision making in a manner that has legal or similarly significant effects on the individual. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61806) to learn more.   
**How we share your information** |  We may share your information with our business units, affiliates, subsidiaries, business partners, customers/members, service providers and/or your representatives, when we believe necessary to protect or enforce our rights or the rights of another user, and as otherwise permitted by law. We do not sell or share information with third parties so that they can independently market their own products or services to you, unless we have explicitly given you the option to opt-in such disclosures. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61774) to learn more.   
**Your Rights Regarding Your Personal Information** |  We provide you with the opportunity to be informed of whether we are processing your information and to access, correct, update, oppose, delete, block, limit or object, upon request and free of charge, to our use of your Personal Information to the extent required by applicable law. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61769) to learn more.   
**Security of Your Information** |  We maintain commercially-reasonable technical, administrative and physical security measures to protect your information. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61780) to learn more.   
**International Transfers** |  We may transfer your information outside of your home country. To protect such information, any such international transfers will be made in accordance with applicable law. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61777) to learn more.   
**Our Retention of Your Information** |  We retain your information to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected, comply with record retention requirements that apply to our business and where required to address legal or compliance matters affecting the information. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61807) to learn more.   
**Cookies and similar Technologies** |  We may use cookies and similar technologies to help deliver our products, services and Sites, offer you a more personalized user experience and market products and services to you. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61773) to learn more.   
**Marketing Communications** |  You can opt out of receiving marketing communications from us. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61771) to learn more.   
**Referrals** |  If you choose to refer an individual about our products or services, to explore a business relationship with us or to use our Sites, we will ask you for the individual’s name and email address for us to send your friend a one-time email to invite him/her to access the specific Site. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61808) to learn more.   
**Links to Other Websites** |  Our Sites may contain links to other websites or services that are not owned or controlled by Nasdaq, including links to websites of our advertisers, sponsors and partners. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61779) to learn more.   
**Use of Sites by Children** |  Our Sites are not intended for use by children under the age of sixteen. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61809) to learn more.   
**Changes to this Privacy Policy** |  You will be notified about any material changes to this Privacy Policy via a posting on our Sites, and as otherwise required by applicable law. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61770) to learn more.   
**Contact Us** |  If you have questions about this Privacy Policy or wish to exercise your rights regarding Personal Information, please contact us at [privacy@nasdaq.com](mailto:privacy@nasdaq.com) or one of the other points of contact listed in this Privacy Policy. You may also contact our Data Protection Official for our EEA Regulated Entities and the Data Protection Authority. Click [here](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61772) to learn more.   
  
## Information about how this policy applies to our global company

As a global organization, different Nasdaq entities, products/services and Sites may be subject to different privacy laws based on where our entity operates, where the products/services are delivered and/or where you are located. For example, the European Union General Data Protection Regulation imposes certain requirements on some Nasdaq entities or services that are not applicable to all of our entities or services. Where this Privacy Policy states that a provision applies “to the extent required by applicable law,” such provision will be applicable only to the extent that Nasdaq is subject to legal requirements imposing it.

For purposes of data protection laws, except where this Privacy Policy does not apply, as described below, the Nasdaq entity that will be the “controller” of your Personal Information will be the entity that delivers the products or services you (or the company for whom you are working or have a business relationship) are receiving or maintains the Site that you are using. You can identify the Nasdaq company that hosts a particular Site through the Site’s footer or “About” link. A list of Nasdaq’s different business locations is available at this site: <https://business.nasdaq.com/discover/nasdaq-locations/index.html>.

Although your data controller may be a specific Nasdaq entity, contact and other customer relationship information that we collect may be held in a customer relationship management or contact database which can be accessed by other Nasdaq entities which may be located globally; further information about [international transfers](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/gdpr-policy.html#tcm:5044-61777) of information is provided below. To the extent required or permitted by applicable law, by visiting or using our Sites, you are consenting to us collecting and processing information about you in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## Situations where this Privacy Policy Does Not Apply

This Privacy Policy also does not apply to Personal Information processed in connection with delivery of services to Nasdaq by suppliers or contractors; such relationships are governed solely by the Personal Information processing terms and conditions between Nasdaq and the supplier/contractor. It also does not apply to job applicants or employees, which are subject to relevant privacy notices.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the extent that:

  * Nasdaq’s contract for delivery of products or service prescribes different Personal Information terms and conditions for the processing of your information;
  * Nasdaq is delivering products or services as a data processor in which the contractual terms and conditions between Nasdaq and the controller/contracting party shall govern;
  * The Site for the products or services sets forth an additional or alternative Privacy Policy; or
  * Applicable law imposes different processing or privacy requirements on your information.

## Information We Collect from You or Your Representative

We only collect information from you/your representative or about you that is reasonably necessary for us to provide the relevant product or service, business relationship and/or communication consistent with the nature of such product, service, business relationship and/or communication. Based on the specific products, services, business relationship or Sites involved as well as requirements under applicable law, we may collect the following categories of personal information (“Personal Information”) that you or your representative (such as your employer, financial services provider, legal representative, company where you are an officer, director or significant shareholder) provide to us:

  * Name;
  * Email address;
  * Social media username;
  * Telephone number;
  * Mailing address;
  * Company;
  * Title;
  * Business contact information;
  * Employment, company officer or director, or shareholder status;
  * Tax or National Identification Number;
  * Date of birth;
  * Trader identification, client identification or trading “short code”;
  * Career or professional history and educational background;
  * Financial holdings information;
  * Your recorded voice (where you are advised in advance of the recording);
  * Photograph;
  * Payment information (e.g., bank account or credit card number);
  * Username and password;
  * Passport or government issued identification information (such as for security purposes when visiting our facilities); and
  * Any other Personal Information you or your representative volunteers on or provides access to via any or our Sites and/or any Nasdaq community forum, social media offering or blog.

We may also automatically collect the following categories of information from devices (e.g., mobile, computer, laptop, tablet) used to visit or use our Sites (“Device Information”):

  * IP address;
  * Device identifier;
  * Log files;
  * Cookies;
  * Clear gifs;
  * Flash LSOs; and
  * Other information as described in our Cookies Policy (Click [here] to view our Cookies Policy).

Certain Device Information may be deemed Personal Information in accordance with applicable law. Personal Information and Device Information are collectively referred to as “information.”

## Information that We Collect About You

Based on the specific products, services, business relationship or Sites involved (as well as requirements under applicable law), we may collect the following categories of Personal Information on our own or from third parties about you in accordance with applicable law:

  * Information about you available in news feeds, exchange data feeds and other public data sources (including the public internet);
  * Information provided by relevant regulators, government agencies and non-government credentialing or professional organizations;
  * Information related to your status under economic sanctions, anti-money laundering and similar laws or other information that may impact our ability to engage in business with you or a company at which you are an employee, officer or director or significant shareholder;
  * Information that you, your employer or other representative makes publicly available via your personal or company website or in social media profiles;
  * Information related to your professional activities (such as consulting to public retirement funds) that is contained in documents released by a governmental body under Freedom of Information Act, Open Government License or similar laws and regulations;
  * Information from event organizers for events that you have attended;
  * Information from companies providing professional contact information to their customers/subscribers; and
  * Other Personal Information to the extent permitted by applicable law and reasonably necessary for the performance of our business obligations, compliance with laws applicable to our business or pursuit of our legitimate business interests.

## How We Use Your Information

The following is an overview of Nasdaq’s purposes for processing Personal Information. Often due to the nature of the product or service involved or the context in which the Personal Information is used, it will be apparent how we intend to use the information. Additional information about processing related to a particular product or service may be separately posted on the relevant Site or contained in the applicable terms and conditions.

We may use the information we collect for the purposes identified below. To the extent required by applicable law, each purpose for the processing of Personal Information is substantiated by one or more lawful bases for processing. Unless otherwise identified with respect to a particular product or service, our processing is done based of one or more of the following:

Purpose of Processing| Bases for Processing  
---|---  
Provide you (or your employer/represented company) with our services and products and communicate with you about your (or your employer/represented company) accounts or use of our products, services and/or Sites| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Legitimate business interests
  * Comply with a legal obligation
  * Consent

Process transactions through one of our services including, but not limited to, processing financial transactions initiated by your or your representative| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Comply with a legal obligation

Comply with our obligations as an exchange, clearinghouse, broker-dealer, central shares depository, pension system administrator and/or other regulated/licensed business including, but not limited to regulations applicable to our EEA Regulated Entities such as, for example, the Markets in Financial Instruments Regulation| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Comply with a legal obligation

Perform transaction and regulatory reporting requirements under applicable law| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Comply with a legal obligation

Perform our obligations as a Self-Regulatory Organization, trading venue and/or market operator including, but not limited to, conducting surveillance of issuers and trading activities, conducting disciplinary proceedings and reporting suspected to misconduct to regulators and other authorities| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Legitimate business interests
  * Comply with a legal obligation

Monitor for security threats and fraud involving the use of our products, services, Sites or physical facilities| 

  * Legitimate business interests
  * Comply with a legal obligation

Maintain your status as a representative of an exchange or clearinghouse member or certified advisor to issuers| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Comply with a legal obligation

Register or establish an account for you (or the company for whom you are an employee, officer or director) as a customer| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Legitimate business interests
  * Comply with a legal obligation

Register you (or your employer/represented company) to receive services or information through one or more of our Sites| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Consent

To the extent permitted by applicable law, identify you (or your employer/represented company) as a prospective customer for products or services and provide you with relevant information and/or invitations to events| 

  * Legitimate business interest
  * Consent

Manage our relationship with you (or your employer/represented company) as a customer, business prospect and/or information recipient| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Legitimate business interest
  * Consent

To pursue or enforce our legal rights related to our business, products, services or Sites and/or defend against claims made against us| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Legitimate business interest

Communicate with you (or your employer/represented company) about your account or use of our products, services or Sites| 

  * Legitimate business interest
  * Consent

Create informational materials and statistical extracts for our products and services| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Legitimate business interest
  * Consent

Develop, provide content for, operate, deliver, and market our services and Sites| 

  * Perform or enter into a contract
  * Legitimate business interest
  * Consent

Improve the quality of our Sites and tailor them to your preferences| 

  * Legitimate business interest
  * Consent

Implement social networking features you have activated (e.g., Facebook “Like” button and LinkedIn integration)| 

  * Consent

With respect to situations where we process Personal Information based on our legitimate business interest, reflecting that we are generally a business-to-business product and service provider, we typically collect and process limited Personal Information about corporate customer points of contact and individuals acting in their professional capacities as part of our overall effect to reduce the privacy impact on individuals. To the extent required by applicable law, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data based on a legitimate interest as legal basis. Please see the section below regarding [your rights](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61769) to find out more. Where processing is based on your consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.

We also use your information for compliance with our company policies and procedures, for accounting and financial purposes, and otherwise as required or permitted by applicable law. If you do not provide us with information as described above, we may not be able to fulfill the applicable purpose of collection, such as completing a contemplated transaction, responding to your queries or providing access to our Sites to you.

## Automated Decision-Making

Nasdaq does not engage decision-making based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning an individual or similarly significantly affects an individual.

As part of Nasdaq’s surveillance programs for its exchanges, we utilize certain software that uses machine intelligence and learning to identify situations that potentially constitute market abuse, insider trading, fraud or violations of our published rules. Such software relies on identifying patterns indicating misconduct based on past activity. The conduct involved may include conduct by a corporate member, trading algorithm or individual action. Alerts are referred for investigation by our Surveillance team which determines which actions to take based on our published rules and applicable law.

## How We Share Your Information

From time to time, to the extent permitted by applicable law and subject to any contractual limitations on sharing Personal Information set forth in a relevant contract for products and services, we may share your information with our affiliates, subsidiaries, business partners, customers/members (such as where we process your Personal Information in connection with your role with your employer or financial services provider), third party service providers and authorities in the following circumstances:

  *  ** _Nasdaq Business Units, Affiliates, Subsidiaries, Business Partners and Customers._** We may share your information with our business units, affiliates, subsidiaries, business partners, and customers in the US and worldwide for purposes identified above. A list of Nasdaq’s offices by country is posted at: <https://business.nasdaq.com/discover/contact-us/index.html>. To the extent required or permitted by applicable law, by visiting or using our Sites or otherwise providing us with your information, you consent to this sharing of your information. Where such consent exists, to opt-out of such sharing, please contact us via email at [privacy@nasdaq.com](mailto:privacy@nasdaq.com) or at the location in the Contact Us section below.
  *  ** _Service Providers._** We may share your information with third parties who perform functions on our behalf (e.g., hosting or operating our services or Sites, processing credit card payments, sending email marketing communications, or data analysis). We do not authorize these third parties to use your information for purposes other than for which it has been provided, and do not authorize these third parties to disclose that information to unauthorized parties. We require these third parties to maintain appropriate security to protect your information from unauthorized access or processing.
  *  ** _As Required or Appropriate by Law._** We may disclose your information to regulatory authorities, courts, and government agencies where we believe that doing so would be in accordance with or permitted or required by any applicable law, regulation or legal process, to defend the interests, rights, and/or property of Nasdaq or others, or to respond to emergencies.
  *  ** _Business Transfers._** We may transfer your information to a third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, brands, affiliates, subsidiaries or other assets. To the extent permitted by applicable law, we may share information with a prospective buyer or transferee of the business as part of the diligence process provided that we require any such third party to maintain the confidentiality of your information and protect it with appropriate technical and organizational security measures. 

We may share your information with other parties as directed by you or subject to your consent. We may also share and otherwise process aggregated information or de-identified information that does not identify you individually with other parties. For example, from time to time, we may utilize survey information collected from you on an aggregate, not individually identifiable, basis. We also use this aggregated or de-identified information for our various business purposes, including the creation and sale of other products and services to our clients and potential clients. This aggregate or de-identified information is not traceable to any particular client or user and will not be used by a third party to contact you.

We do not share, sell, rent or trade your information to our service providers or business partners for their own direct marketing purposes, unless we have explicitly given you the option to opt-in or opt-out of such disclosures.

## Marketing Communications

We process Personal Information within the scope of our marketing and market segmentation. With market segmentation, we mean that we categorize our customer base based on professional affiliations and functions, alignment with our services and products and information gathered from public sources of information. For customers or users of our Sites, we may also use information gathered from your use of our products, services and/or Sites for marketing purposes. You always have right to request that we stop using your personal data for direct marketing purposes.

To the extent required by applicable law, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data based on a legitimate interest as legal basis. You also always have the right to withdraw your consent at any time when we need your consent in order to process your personal data. If you withdraw your consent, you will no longer receive information and offers that are tailored for you. Please see the section [below](https://business.nasdaq.com/privacy-statement/index.html#tcm:5044-61769) for more information about your rights.

If you no longer wish to receive marketing communications from us, you may opt-out of receiving marketing-related emails by: (1) using the unsubscribe method provided in our communications; (2) if you created an online account when you registered to receive our emails, you may log-in to your account on the applicable Site and make changes to your communication preferences; or (3) you can opt out by updating your preferences in the Email Alert section of our Sites. In particular, you have the right to object our use of your personal information for direct marketing and in certain other situations (in accordance with applicable law) by contacting us at [privacy@nasdaq.com](mailto:privacy@nasdaq.com). If you are having difficulty unsubscribing from our email marketing communications using the above methods, please contact us as at [privacy@nasdaq.com](mailto:privacy@nasdaq.com).

We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable as required by applicable law. Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes, to complete any transactions that you began prior to your request, or for other purposes as required or permitted by applicable law. In addition, please note that even if you opt-out of receiving marketing communications from one or all of our Sites, we may need to send you service-related communications.

## Your Rights Regarding Your Personal Information

To the extent required by applicable law, in our capacity as the controller of your Personal Information, we will also provide you with the opportunity to be informed of whether we are processing your Personal Information and at any time to access, correct, update, oppose, delete, block, limit or object to our use of your Personal Information. The foregoing rights will be afforded to you free of charge (except to the extent that your requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive, in which case, we may charge an administrative fee or refuse to meet your request). Please note that legal obligations that apply to our business – for example, financial regulations that apply to our EEA Regulated Business - may prevent us from immediately deleting parts of your information. To exercise your rights, please contact us as detailed under the Contact Us heading below.

To prevent fraudulent activity, we may require you to authenticate your identity when you contact us. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable and within timeframes required by applicable law. Please note that in some instances, due to the nature of the information that we receive, we may require you to provide additional information that will help us identify which information is yours. For requests subject to the European General Data Protection Regulation, we will respond to your request within one month of our receipt of it. We may extend this period by two further months taking into account the complexity of your request or the number of requests that we have received; we will inform you of any such extension within one month of receiving your request along with the reasons for the delay and information about your right to file a complaint with the supervisory authority.

The following sets out a summary of your rights to the extent that your Personal Information is processed subject to the European General Data Protection Regulation:

  *  _Right to access, rectification, erasure and restriction of processing._ You have the right to request: 
    * Access to your personal data. This means that you have the right to request information on our use of your Personal Information. You also have the right to request a copy of the Personal Information being processed at no cost. However, we may charge you a reasonable administrative fee to provide you with additional copies of the Personal Information. If you make your access request by electronic means such as email, we will provide you with the information in a commonly used electronic format.
    * Rectification of your personal data. We will at your request, or at our own initiative, rectify, anonymise, erase or complement Personal Information that you or we discover is inaccurate, incomplete or misleading. You also have the right to complete the Personal Information with additional data if relevant information is missing.
    * Erasure of your personal data. You have the right to request that we erase your Personal Information if we do no longer have an acceptable reason for processing the data. Given this, erasure shall be made by us if:
    * the Personal Information is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected,
    * we use your Personal Information with your consent and you withdraw your consent,
    * you object to the processing of your Personal Information based on our legitimate interest and there is no overriding legitimate ground for the processing,
    * the Personal Information has not been lawfully processed,
    * we are required to erase the Personal Information due to a legal obligation, or
    * you are a child and we have collected the personal data in relation to the offer of information society services. 

However, there might be requirements under applicable law, or other compelling reasons, that prevents us from immediately erasing your Personal Information. In such case, we will stop using your Personal Information for any other reasons than to comply with the applicable law, or the relevant compelling reason _._

  * Right to restrict processing: This means that we temporarily restrict the processing of your Personal Information. You have the right to request restriction of the processing when: 
    * you have requested rectification of your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy, during the period of time we are verifying the accuracy of the data,
    * the processing is unlawful and you do not want the Personal Information to be erased,
    * as data controller, we no longer need the Personal Information for the purposes for which it was collected, but you require us to retain the information for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims, or
    * you have objected to our legitimate interest for the processing in accordance with this Privacy Policy, during the period of time we determine whether the legitimate interest overrides your privacy rights.

We will take all reasonable and possible actions to notify any recipients of your Personal Information regarding any rectification, erasure or restrictions carried out by us. At your request, we will also inform you with which third parties we have shared your Personal Information.

  *  _Right to object to processing._ You have the right to object to the processing of your Personal Information based on our legitimate interest. If you object to such processing, we will only continue with the processing if we have a compelling legitimate reason for the processing that outweighs your interest, rights or freedoms, or if continued processing is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of a legal claim.
  *  _Right to portability._ You have the right to receive certain of your Personal Information in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the right to transmit those data to another controller. You only have this right when your personal data is processed by automated means and our legal basis for the processing is performance of a contract between you and us.
  *  _Right to lodge a complaint._ You have the right to lodge any complaints regarding our processing of your personal data with the supervisory authority.

##  Security of Your Information

We take reasonable technical, administrative and physical security measures to protect your information, including applying generally accepted industry standards to protect the information submitted to us during transmission and once we receive it. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure, so we unfortunately cannot guarantee absolute security. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (e.g., if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), please contact us immediately as detailed under the “Contact Us” heading below.

## Retention of Your Information

We will retain your information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy and as otherwise needed to comply with applicable law and recordkeeping requirements or to address any complaints, challenges, legal or compliance matters related to the information.

##  Cookies and Similar Technologies 

When you use our Sites, we along with our affiliates, subsidiaries and third party service providers may use “cookies” and similar technologies (e.g., log files, clear gifs, pixel tags and Flash LSOs) (collectively, “technology”). This technology may involve placing small files/code on your device or browser that serve a number of purposes, such as remembering your preferences (e.g., language) and generally improving your experience on our Sites. Specifically, we may use such technology for purposes such as to:

  * Provide us with general analytics about our Sites, including demographic information in a non-identifiable form, in order to improve our Sites’ performance and customize users’ experience;
  * Enable us to help you make better use of our services or Sites such as by suggesting how you can improve your use of different features or functionality or help address technical issues that you encounter in using our services or Sites;
  * Support security measures, such as requiring re-login into your account or additional authentication when using a new device to access our Sites;
  * Measure the success of our marketing campaigns and compile statistics about the Site’s usage and email response rates;
  * Allow you to engage in our social media offerings on our Sites (e.g., Facebook “Like” button and LinkedIn integration); and
  * More effectively market our Sites and advertise other Sites that may be of interest to you. 

To learn more about the technology used on our Sites and how to disable some of the technology, visit our more comprehensive [Cookie Statement](https://business.nasdaq.com/cookie-statement).

## Referrals

If you choose to use our referral service to tell someone about our products or services or Sites, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will send your referral a one-time email to invite him/her to access the Site or with information about the product or service, and store his/her email address for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your referral may contact us as detailed under the “Contact Us” heading below to request we remove this information from our database.

## Links to Other Websites

Our Sites may contain links to other websites or services that are not owned or controlled by Nasdaq, including links to websites of our advertisers, sponsors and partners. This Privacy Policy only applies to information collected by our Sites. We have no control over these third party websites, and your use of third party websites and features are subject to privacy policies posted on those websites. We are not responsible or liable for the privacy or business practices of any third party websites linked to our Sites. Your use of third parties’ websites linked to our Sites is at your own risk, so we encourage you to read the privacy policies of any linked third party websites when you leave one of our Sites.

We may use third party payment services to process purchases made through the Sites. If such service is made available and you wish to make a purchase through the Site, your Personal Information may be collected by the third party (and not by us). In that case, the information you provide to the third party will be subject to that third party’s privacy policy and not this Privacy Policy.

## Use of Sites by Children

None of our Sites are targeted for use by children under the age of sixteen. We do not target any of our products or services or Site content/features for use by children of such age.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy 

Except to the extent limited by applicable law, we reserve the right to update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices by prominently posting notice of the update on our Sites. Unless otherwise noted, any updates will become effective 30 days after posting the updates to the Privacy Policy, and apply to all information collected about you. If we make any changes to this Privacy Policy that materially impact previously collected information about you, we will, to the extent that we have your email address, notify you by email.

##  Contact Us 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or information we have collected about you, please contact us by email at [privacy@nasdaq.com](mailto:privacy@nasdaq.com) or by postal mail at:

Office of General Counsel – Privacy Team   
Nasdaq, Inc.   
805 King Farm Blvd   
First Floor   
Rockville, MD 20850

Office of General Counsel – Stockholm Office   
Tullvaktsvägen 15,   
10578 Stockholm   
Sweden

For our EEA Regulated Entities, you may also contact our Data Protection Officer:

Advokatfirman Lindahl KB,   
Box 1065,   
101 39 Stockholm,   
Sweden   
Att: Caroline Olstedt Carlström – Nasdaq Data Protection Officer

With respect to Personal Information processing subject to European Union jurisdiction, in addition to contacting our business contacts and Data Protection Officer (for our EEA Regulated Businesses), you may also contact a data protection supervisory authority. Within Europe, Nasdaq’s headquarters is located in Sweden, making the responsible data protection supervisory authority:

 **The Swedish Data Protection Authority**

Contact details:

Telefon: 08-657 61 00   
E-post: [datainspektionen@datainspektionen.se](mailto:datainspektionen@datainspektionen.se)  
Fax: 08-652 86 52

Postadress:   
Datainspektionen   
Box 8114   
104 20 Stockholm

***
